rtd-denver.com 2013-06-07

# RTD | Privacy Policy

**At RTD, we are committed to protecting the privacy of our customers and visitors to our website. The following privacy policy statement specifies what information we collect on our website(s) and how we use it.**

## Collection and use of personal information 

* * *

There are sections on the website where we ask you to provide personal information so that we may follow-up with you. Such personal information may be required to subscribe to email notifications, apply for a job online, complete surveys, or fill out other forms, such as the customer comment form. The personal information collected may include your name, email address, phone number, street address, etc. We will not lease, sell or otherwise release your personal information to third parties not affiliated with us unless disclosure is required by law. We will use the personal information you provide only to respond to your request or inquiry.

We will not send you unsolicited emails. If you sign up to receive email notifications from us, you will receive only the information you sign up to receive. If you wish to opt out or revise the email notifications you receive, [update your preferences](https://public.govdelivery.com/accounts/COTRANRTD/subscribers/new?preferences=true) here. 

## Collection and use of non-personal information

* * *

We collect aggregated (non-personal) information such as Internet domain, IP address, browser, operating system, referring/exit pages, date and time stamp, etc. from all visitors to our website for statistical purposes. Aggregated information does not include personal identifying information. The information collected is used for analysis and reporting, providing information on site trends and usage so that we can continue to enhance our site based on our customers’ needs. We may disclose anonymous, aggregated data to third parties working with RTD or include such data in public records. 

### Google Analytics

RTD uses Google Analytics, a web analytics tool that helps website owners understand how visitors engage with their website. The [Google Analytics Terms of Service](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/tos.html), which all Analytics customers must adhere to, prohibits the tracking or collection of personal information using Google Analytics or associating personal information with web analytics information. Visit [Google Analytics Privacy Overview](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html) for more information. 

### GovDelivery 

RTD uses GovDelivery, a third-party digital subscription management service to manage email subscriptions and communications. GovDelivery does not share information gathered through its clients with third parties for promotional purposes. Visit [GovDelivery’s Legal and Privacy Overview](http://www.govdelivery.com/privacy) for more information. 

### Yahoo Store 

RTD’s Online Store is hosted by Yahoo! Store. Yahoo! hosts the store pages, ordering system, and order data. Yahoo! automatically collects order information but may only use this information in the aggregate. If you accessed this store through Yahoo! Shopping, Yahoo! also automatically collects information about your shopping experience. Visit [Yahoo! Privacy Policy](http://privacy.yahoo.com/privacy/us/) for more information.

### Smart card (MyRide, EcoPass, CollegePass) 

RTD's Smart card revenue collection system collects ridership data, financial transaction data when a card is loaded with fare values or pass products, and written or email correspondance between you and RTD regarding your smart card account. If you register your smart card to protect its value, the system will also collect your smart card account number, name, email address, phone number, and home address. View the full RTD Smart Card Privacy Policy. 

## Compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act

* * *

RTD complies with the requirements of the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act. RTD will not target its offerings towards or knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. 

## Cookies

* * *

A cookie is a piece of text that can be stored by your web browser on your computer. Typically, cookies are used to tailor a website to better suit your interests and preferences. RTD-Denver.com does not use cookies outside of those that Google Analytics uses to track site statistics.

## Security

* * *

To ensure site security, RTD employs software programs to monitor network traffic and identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

## Links to other websites 

* * *

This privacy statement applies solely to RTD’s website. Links to other websites are included to provide our riders with supplemental information. If you choose to follow these links, you are leaving RTD’s website and are subject to the privacy policies of those sites. RTD is not responsible for content or policies of those websites. 

## Consent

* * *

By using the RTD website, you consent to the collection and use of information described in this privacy policy.

## Policy updates 

* * *

This page will be updated with our current privacy policy so you will always be aware of the type of information we collect and how we use it. RTD reserves the right to update this privacy policy at any time. 

## Questions

* * *

If you have questions about this privacy policy statement, please contact us. 

Copyright © 2011 The Regional Transportation District. All rights reserved.  
RTD, 1600 Blake Street, Denver, CO 80202

Last updated October 2012
